tai! kait kia1 xizi. pai2 kua2 huo2 pua2 a. / Hello everyone. This is Qa Fopwa.
at / And
pai2 pet2 sep nuok2. / This is Putt Zupnuok.
ua ka1 kia1 / And today,
pai2 at pet2 sep nuok2 at kuai1 gau2 kak / Me and Putt Zupnuok and Kwai Gaukak
sak2 ka1 / came here
ua pai2 ge tu2 cet2 kaik a. / And we play Setkaik.
hut2 a! / Let's get started!
iei2 / spring
sak2! / Come on!
om2 / three.
ik2 / two.
mok1 / Go!
a. ka1 kait. / Oh. That is good.
ua... / Then...
mok1 ka1 hue. / I'll go here
uai1? / General, right?
mok1 kauk2. / I'll advance the Pawn.
kit kait. / Very good.
kit pek1 a. / Very strong.
ua / Well then
pai2 mok1 ka1 hue. / I'll go here
ua pai2 mok1 huap1 gua2. / Then I'll advance the Archer and it's an Aiming Archer.
huap1 gua2. / An Aiming Archer?
he he hen. / Hmm, hmm.
aim2. / Yup.
ka1 kait a. / Good
kait a po1. / It's a good way.
om2. / three.
ua pai2 bap / Then I, too,
huap1 gua2 a. / Aiming Archer.
huap1 gua2 a. / Ah, Aiming Archer.
n... / Hmm
hop1 mua2 gua2. / Take that Archer.
gua2. hen hop1 gua2. / Archer, oh do you take an Archer?
ua pai2 / Then I
sui1 kauk2 hop1 gua2 a. ka1 kait yn2? / take an Archer with a Pawn. Isn't it good?
ua pai2 mok1 gua2 a. / Then I'll move the Archer.
mok1 gua2 a. / Ah, you move the Archer.
kit kait. / Very good.
ua pai2 hia1 mok1 kaun1. / Then I want to move the Chariot.
ua pai2 mun1 py mok1 kaun1 a. / But I can't move it.
a. mun1 mun1 mun1. / Ah, no, no.
aim2 yn2? / Is there any?
pai2 mok1 py ka1 hue. / I can go here.
ua ua ua / Oops
ua pai2 mok1 pai2 tuk2 / Then I move the Shaman,
hop1 kua2. / taking an Officer.
o / Oh
a! / Ah!
ua pai2 / Then I
a. kait. / Oh, that's good
pai2 kau... mok1 pai2 kaun1. / I, the Chariot... I move the Chariot.
tai! pai2 mok1 ka1 hue a! / Alright! Then I'll move to here!
uai1 aim2 tam2 hue a. / The General is in the Tam's Field...
tam2 hue a uai1. / General in the Tam's Field.
a. / Oh.
om2. / three.
a! mua2 hop1... / Oh, you're taking it...
em / Yup
hop1 uai1 hem / If you take a General
uai1? a. / General? Oh.
uai1? / General?
hop1 uai1 hem / If you take a General
pai2 py zau huep2 hia1 a. / You can make "The Culture".
ua pai2 hia1 / Then I want to
maun1 / Horse.
maun1 yn2? / Horse?
ia. maun1. / Yes. Horse.
y kauk2. y kauk2. / Or a Pawn. Or  a Pawn.
maun1 / A Horse
y kauk2. / Or a Pawn.
maun1 y kauk2 / A Horse or a Pawn.
em... / Hmm…
pai2 hia1 hop1 hauk2. / I want to capture a Pawn.
a! / Ah!
a. mok1 ut2. / Oh, you're go down?
mok1 ut2. / Went down.
pai2 hia1 ka1 mok1 kait. / I think this move is good.
kait yn2? / Is it good?
kait. / good.
m... / Hmm...
kait a. / good.
"ut2" mok1 hem mua2 "ut2" ie ka1 kait a. / Going "down" would be "at a disadvantage" in this battle.
kait nan2? / Doing what is a good one?
nan2 kait a? / What is good?
ua... / Then...
mok1. / I'll move.
tam2!? / Tam!?
tam2... / The Tam...
a... / Oh no oh no
tarm / Tam...
nan2 ka1 kait... / Why is this good...
tam2 ie. pai2 mok1 ka1 hue. / Move the Tam here.
a!? / Eh!?
nn / Yup
ua pai2 tuk2 mok1. / The Shaman moves here.
ua / Well then
aim2 tam2 hue a. / It's in the Tam's Field.
tam2 hue a. et? / Tam's Field. eh?
ua / Well then
pai2 sau2 ut2! / I'll climb up and down!
ua... pai2 kut2 xy1 / Then... I throw the Sticks
a...!! / Aaaaah!!!
a! om2! / Alright! three!
pai2 hop1 io! / I take the king!
ua pai2 zau huep2 hia1 at io! / And "The Culture" and "The King" are completed!
taxt? / End the season?
ua pai2 nun1 ik2 mak2! / And 12 points.
tymor? tymor? / Go again? Go again?
nun1 ik2. / 12.
ua... / Well then
ta xot1! / I end the season!
a kait a! / Oh, that was good.
xo1 / summer
kait a! / Good!
kait a! kait a! / Good, good.
kut2 xy1! / I throw the Sticks!
kut2 xy1 a kaik! / The battle of throwing the sticks!
sak2! / Come on!
a! / Ah!
bap! / the same!
bap a. / Ah, it's the same.
ty mok1! / Redo!
ap1 kak kut2 xy1 / For four times we threw the sticks...
ik2. / two.
ap1. / four.
pai2 huap1 gua2 a. / Aiming Archer.
huap1 gua2? / An Aiming Archer?
ka1 kait yn2? pai2 mun1 can2 a. / Is this good? I do not know.
mun1!? / zero!?
nan2 tun2 sak2 ka1 hue!? / What god came here!?
huap1 gua2 a. / Aiming Archer.
mua2 bap mun1. / You'll also have zero.
ty huap1 gua2 a. / Again, Aiming Archer.
mua2 xy1 mun1. / You'll have zero Sticks.
pai2 mun1 aim2 hop1 non1 tun2 a. / I don't have a bad god.
sak2! / Come on!
kait a! / Alright!
ua hop1 mua2 a kait. / Then it seems good to capture it.
ka1 kait po1. / That's a good way.
ua pai2 hop1. / I'll capture it.
huap1 gua2 a. / An Aiming Archer?
pai2 mok1 ka1 hue. / Then here.
vynut. / Good.
y-nut yn2? / Good, isn't it?
lip zep1? / Linepāine?
a. lip zep1. / Yup.
mua2 py zep1 lip zep1 yn2? / Can you speak Linepāine?
a... mun1. / No.
mun1 py. / I can't.
mun1 py. / Oh, You can't.
pai2 py zep1 "salarua". / I can say "Hello".
o. / Ah.
or. / Ah.
pai2 hia1 kait. / I think it's good.
pai2 ly mak1! / I have to fight against it.
gua2 dat2 sak2 pai2 a kaik dat2! / An Archer is approaching us!
pai2 mok1 sau2 io a. / I move the King forward.
io a? / King?
pai2 ly hop1 ka1? / Should I capture it?
pai2 ly mok1... pai2 ly hop1 ka1. / I should go... I should capture it.
gua2 ik2 hi1! / A pair of bows!
ka1 kait! / This is good!
ua ie ka1 tu2 mun1 kait a. / But in this game it is not good.
zau nan2 yn2? / What are you doing?
tarfe. / Tam's Field.
a! / Oh!
cene co... / You can...
a. kait a. / Oh, nice.
pai2 io mok1 guk2 hop1 ie mua2 a. / My king will be taken by you.
ua tam2 nua2 a... / But the Tam's Water...
hop1 ka1... / Do I capture...
o. xy1!? / Oh, Sticks!?
sak2! / Come on!
kait! / Good!
or. / Ah
nan2 cuk2 sui1 om2 gua2? / Who would ever use three Archers
gua2 gua2 gua2 / Archer Archer Archer
ut2 kauk2. / I retreat the Pawn.
pai2 hop1 maun1 a. / I'll capture a Horse.
maun1 a. / Horse.
vynut. / Good.
sak2 / It came.
kait tun2 sak2 pai2 a. / A good god has come.
pai2 mok1 hop1 mua2 a gua2. / I'll take an Archer.
tuk2 ie ka1 hue. / The Shaman to here.
nan2 hue mok1 yn2? / Where will it go?
pai2 hia1 hop1 maun1. / I want to capture a Horse.
ka1 hue. / here
py hop1 ka1 kua2. / Can take this Archer.
ja, ja. / Yes Yes
pai2 mok1 ut2 a. / I'll move back.
em... mok1 ka1. / I'll go here
sak2! / Come on!
em. kait a. kait a. / Yes Yes
ua pai2 mok1 ka1 hue. / Then here.
a. tam2 hue a. / Oh. It's Tam's Field.
mal, deliu co... / And you should...
deliu co amol gustu fqa mol. / You should put your Archer here. This exists.
cene co afnar fqa ad fqa. / You can remove this and this.
nan2 mak2 yn2? / How many points?
un1? un1 un1. / Five points? Five points five points.
un1 yn2. / Five
un1 ua... / If five...
ta xot1 yn2? / End the season?
ty mok1? / Go again?
em. ta xot1. / Hmm. I end the season.
ta xot1!? mua2 mok1 ut2 yn2? / You'll end the season!? You'll lose, you know?