Hello everyone. This is Quafo.
And
This is Pezepunuk.
And today,
Me and Pezepunuk and Kuiui Gaukaku
I'm here
And we play Setkaik.
Let's get started!
spring
Come on!
three.
two.
go!
Oh good.
Then...
Let's go here
General, right?
Let's advance the soldiers.
Very good.
Very strong
Well then
I'll go here
Then advance the bow and it's a constant bow.
A constant bow?
Hmm, hmm.
Yup.
Good
It's a good road.
three.
Then I too
Constant bow.
A constant bow?
Hmm
Take that bow.
Bow, oh do you take a bow?
Then I
Take a bow with a soldier. Isn't it good?
Then move the bow.
Will you move the bow~~
very good.
Then I want to move the car.
But I can't move it.
Ah, different, different.
Is there?
You can go here.
Oops
Then proceed with the shrine maiden.
Take a brush
Oh
Ah!
Then I
Oh good
Move the car... move the car.
Alright! Then here!
The shogun is in the Imperial Palace...
General of the Imperial Palace.
Oh.
three.
Oh
Yup
If you take a general
Sho? Oh.
Sho?
If you take a general
You can make a "culture".
Then this is
Horse.
Horse?
so. Horse.
Or soldiers. Or soldiers.
Horse
Or soldiers.
Horse or soldier.
HM…
I want to get soldiers.
Ah!
Oh, go down?
Went down.
I think this move is good.
Is it good?
good.
Hmm...
Going "down" would be "at a disadvantage" in this battle.
What is good?
What is good
Then...
Let's move.
Emperor! ?
The emperor...
Ahhhhh
Emperor...
Why this is good...
Move the emperor here.
e! ?
Yup
The shrine moves here.
Well then
I'm in the Imperial Palace.
Emperor's office. eh?
Well then
Climb up and down!
Then... throw the throwing rod
Aa! !!
Alright! three!
Take the king!
And "Culture" and "King" are completed!
Last season?
And 12 points.
Rerun? Rerun?
12.
Well then
The end of the season!
Oh, good.
summer
Alright!
Okay.
Throw a throwing rod!
Fight throwing throwers!
Come on!
Ah!
the same!
Is it the same~
again!
I threw a throwing bar four times...
two.
four.
Constant bow
A constant bow?
Is this good? do not know.
zero! ?
What god came here! ?
Constant bow.
That's zero too, right?
Another constant bow.
There are no throwing rods, right?
I don't have a god.
Come on!
Alright!
Then it seems good to take it.
It's a good road.
I'll take it.
A constant bow?
Then here.
Good
Good idea?
Lipaline?
Yup.
Can speak Lipaline?
can not speak.
Can't you talk?
"Hello" it can be said.
Oh
I think it's good.
I have to fight.
A bow is approaching us!
Raise the king.
King?
What to take
Should go... should take
A pair of bows!
this is good!
But this play is not good.
What are you doing?
Emperor's office.
Ah!
I can do this.
How nice.
My king will be taken by you.
But the imperial water...
Do you take...
Oh, throwing stick! ?
Come on!
Alright!
Oh
Who uses three bows
Bow bow bow
Lower the soldiers.
Let's take a horse.
Is it a horse?
good.
I came.
A good god has come.
Let's take a bow.
The shrine here.
Where are you going?
I want to get a horse.
here
I can take this bow.
Yes Yes
Let's go down.
Let's go here
Come on!
Yes Yes
Then here.
Oh
And this should be
You should put your bow here. This is
This and this can be removed.
How many points?
Five points? Five points five points.
Five
If five...
Last season?
Rerun?
Hmm. Last season.
The end of the season! ? Will you lose?